Sura Karnawi

D.I.	4 6 4 7 000 0004
Phone	+1 647-939-9331
Address	M2J 3C7, Toronto
Email	sk@sura.me
Website	https://sura.me/
Github	https://github.com/karnawis
Professional profile	 A passionate individual and eager learner bringing a lot of software development experience & leadership abilities in Agile methodologies. My software development experience spans small startups to large corporations, serving millions of users through sites like bbc.co.uk. I'm well-versed in the full software development lifecycle, from conception to deployment, including user research, development with Javascript, Node JS, scaling resources and ongoing maintenance. I'm a STEM speaker and an advocate for accessible design. In my spare time, I'm an artist and a community contributor.
Technical Skills	
Programming & Tools	Javascript, Typescript, HTML, SCSS, REACT, Node.js, RESTful API's, Node.js, Next.js, Python, ABAP, Headless CMS (Contentful, Wordpress, Drupal), GraphQL DepOps, CI/CD, CircleCl Jenkins, SQL, MongoDB, Data Dog, Docker, AWS, Azure, SAP, Paas, Saas, Authentication OAuth 2.0, Git, Github Copilot
Work History	
Work motory	
2021 - 2024	 Studio Lead & Full Stack Developer, Orangutan Matter Studio, Toronto, Canada Oversaw project deliverables, milestones, & development timelines in an agile environment, leading software development from conception, deployment & beyond. Translated business needs into actionable development plans, ensuring alignment with stakeholder/clients objectives. Gathered and analyzed requirements from stakeholder & clients. Guided cross-functional teams across all development phases Conducted code reviews to uphold coding standards, fostering a culture of continuous improvement & code quality. Secured & maintained partnerships such as Sony and Microsoft. Oversaw and contributed to integrating new and existing features across games and other platforms, enhancing functionality and user experience. Contributed to porting projects to various environments with different backend infrastructures. Contributed to the implementation of features for Xbox integration into Unity using Game Development Kit (GDK), API, and sandbox environment. Developed & maintained services and applications using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python leveraging, cloud services, and APIs.

Sura Karnawi

- Led user research and playtesting, making data-driven decisions to enhance user experiences while maintaining the product vision.
- Pioneered and developed cutting-edge techniques and workflows for transitioning traditional art forms into digital formats, utilized Al tools.
- · Mentored and supported developers, collaborators.
- · Created comprehensive guides and documentation for future maintenance
- · Collaborate with the product and design teams to develop and implement new frontend features, ensuring a seamless user experience.

2019 - 2021

Software Engineer, BBC (British Broadcasting Company), England

- Developed high-profile websites and applications, including solutions to BBC News and iPlayer serving millions, as part of a team of engineers, product managers, and designers in Agile methodology
- Develop and implement new features.
- · Pioneered and used the most relevant technologies and practices such as vanilla Javascripts, React, Typescript, Node.js, SCSS..etc.
- · Reviewed and provided constructive feedback on code to ensure compatibility
- Developed in mode (TDD) and (BDD) modes
- · Led live demos, retrospective meetings, and judged as panelist in hackathons.
- · Worked on BBC's Cosmos deployment system, CI automation services Jenkins.
- · Contributed to various technical domains, including CRM integration, cloud-based Paas, Saas solutions, enhancing project capabilities & scalability.
- · Participated in scaling infrastructure without downtime around major events like elections, sport & Royal family events.
- Monitored & utilized tools like DataDog for metrics collection, reducing operational costs.
- Participated in engineering meeting decisions around reducing cost & maintaining performance.
- · Championed for increasing adaptation of accessibility standards in development.
- · Implementing Optimizely for multivariate (MVT), A/B testing of new features.

2016 - 2019

Frontend Developer, Transport for Greater Manchester

- Developed and maintained websites and applications including Transport for Greater Manchester (tfgm.com), using Python, JavaScript, Angular, and React while utilizing cloud services.
- · Contributed to various technical domains, including CRM integration, cloud-based Paas, Saas solutions, enhancing project capabilities & scalability.
- · Created and maintained microservices, migrating applications to modern frameworks with Azure cloud services.
- · Implemented TDD practices to ensure high-quality and reliable code for transport-related applications.
- · Integrated features and capabilities to meet business and stakeholder needs.
- · Modernized and automated the build and delivery process for websites.
- Implemented headless CMS solutions with Contentful, WordPress & Drupal.

Sura Karnawi

	Participated in the engineering team's on-call rotation.
2016 - present	Self Employed - Sura Creativity Ltd., Manchester - Toronto, ON, Canada · Created & maintained websites and applications, headless CMS websites with Drupal, Wordpress and Contentful.
2012 – 2015	 Front End Developer Developer, Soft Gravity, Toronto, ON, Canada Developing, designed and maintained website and mobile applications like Pan Am games Toronto 2014 for the 2015 event using JS, Unroole CMS.
2009 – 2011	Application developer, Drive Medical Canada Inc., Richmond Hill Automated SAP manual reports by developing macros in Abap, VB.NET to manage distributor inventory through their online portals
2008	Other Jobs in the STEM field
Education	
April 2012	Project Management & Website and Application Development Certificate, Seneca College, Markham, Ontario, Canada
June 2008	B.Sc. Computer Science Degree, Baghdad University, Baghdad, Iraq
Contributions & Achievements	 Rising Star Indie Cup Canada Studio Nomination 2023 on Title Unleaving BBC Platforms Development & Design Contribution 202 Released BBC Personalization Transport for Greater Manchester 2019 Accessibility Award-winning tfgm.com PAN AM Games Toronto Website 2015 CMS solution - Core team STEM Speaker 2021 - Present Delivered talks & events to raise awareness about diversity and inclusion
Activities	
2021- Present	Women Representation in STEM Speaker e.i BBC WiStem & Pixelles Speaker
2012 - Present	Art Battle Volunteer & Artist, Toronto, ON, Canada
2016	Barnardo's Believe in Children Volunteer, Manchester, UK
2015	Face Painter, Sick Kids, Toronto, ON, Canada
2012 - 2014	Web Development Teacher., Yorkville Media Center, Canada
2011 - 2013	Special Events Volunteer , Toronto Region Branch (UNACTO)
2009 - 2010	Salvation Army Meighen Manor - Story Teller & Artist, Toronto, ON
2008-2009	Outreach Worker/Designer United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), Damascus, Syria
Languages	
	English (fluent), Arabic (fluent), French (basic)